<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Atari on Garcia&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</title>
    <link>https://rakhama.com/series/atari/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Atari on Garcia&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 19:14:39 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rakhama.com/series/atari/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mystery of the Atari ST&#39;s Bad DMA: Solved?</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/atari-st-bad-dma-solved/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 19:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/atari-st-bad-dma-solved/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I set up my own SD-HDD solution based on the wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/retro16/acsi2stm&#34;&gt;ACSI2STM&lt;/a&gt; project, I found the hard drive was becoming corrupted pretty soon after setting it up. I thought it might have been my dodgy soldering or something funny about the way I had everything set up. Turns out I simply hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard about &lt;a href=&#34;https://exxosforum.co.uk/articles/DMA.html&#34;&gt;Bad DMA&lt;/a&gt;. A local Atari enthusiast meetup later and a solution was proposed; swap the 68000 chip for a newer, lower power and subsequently less noisy version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It worked!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOS Is Rubbish</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/tos-is-rubbish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 08:12:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/tos-is-rubbish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never noticed it growing up but I see it now, TOS is profoundly flakey. My ST has a TOS 1.62 ROM built in and it does not play nice with hard drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a simple solution to this, use the wonderful open source &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/emutos/emutos&#34;&gt;EmuTOS&lt;/a&gt; instead. Now I&amp;rsquo;m not resourceful enough to go writing EmuTOS to a flash ROM but my ST does have enough RAM that I can easily get away with loading it up from the hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Finally Got an ST Again</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/i-finally-got-an-st-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:03:49 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/i-finally-got-an-st-again/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a whole number of years since I owned an Atari ST. Well over 20. In my youth I (and by &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; I mean &amp;ldquo;my family&amp;rdquo;) had two, both of which packed in after some time, the last kicking the bucket in the mid to late 90s. Ever since then I&amp;rsquo;ve longed to have another, even as I moved briefly to the Amiga before joining the PC train in 1999.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>