<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Garcia&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</title>
    <link>https://rakhama.com/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Garcia&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 16:20:25 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rakhama.com/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug Server Hosted Blazor Web Assembly in VS Code</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/debug-server-hosted-blazor-wasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 16:20:25 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/debug-server-hosted-blazor-wasm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A published Blazor WebAssembly instance is just a collection of files that can be loaded into a browser. If these files are hosted on the API, running the API means the UI is running as well, probably from the same address. In this case it&amp;rsquo;s a little different to debug compared to launching it standalone, but not any more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solid Principles: A Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/solid-principles-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 16:49:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/solid-principles-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a single-page cheat sheet that summarised SOLID software development principles, so I made one. For each of the letters in SOLID (Single Responsibility, Open/Closed, Liskov Substitution, Interface Segregation, Dependency Inversion) there are a couple of bullet points explaining the benefits of adopting them and the smells that betray their violation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asp.NET Self-Signed Certificates and Fedora</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/asp-net-self-signed-certs-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 16:12:24 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/asp-net-self-signed-certs-fedora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I spent a bit of time fighting with certificates in an ASP.NET application I&amp;rsquo;m working on. The scenario is we have Blazor Server communicating with a Minimal API. Debugging locally I was struggling to get the two to communicate, with errors like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remote certificate is invalid because of errors in the certificate chain: UntrustedRoot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post #1: A Git Trick</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/a-git-trick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 19:37:16 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/a-git-trick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! I&amp;rsquo;ve started a new blog. For my first post I&amp;rsquo;m going to share a Git configuration trick that I often use to work around this dang ol&amp;rsquo; error message when trying to push a locally created branch to a remote repository:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>