<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>future reference on Garcia&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</title>
    <link>https://rakhama.com/tags/future-reference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in future reference on Garcia&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 14:34:41 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://rakhama.com/tags/future-reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Blazor With MVVM</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/blazor-with-mvvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 14:34:41 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/blazor-with-mvvm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MVVM is a development pattern that has been around for a while now. It was designed to facilitate the development of WPF applications for Windows and is still used for the likes of &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/architecture/maui/mvvm&#34;&gt;Maui&lt;/a&gt; apps. I reckon it has a place in Blazor apps as a neat way to separate view from logic, and as a sort of volatile state management for when you don&amp;rsquo;t want state to persist between pages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug Server Hosted Blazor Web Assembly in VS Code</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/debug-server-hosted-blazor-wasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 16:20:25 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/debug-server-hosted-blazor-wasm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A published Blazor WebAssembly instance is just a collection of files that can be loaded into a browser. If these files are hosted on the API, running the API means the UI is running as well, probably from the same address. In this case it&amp;rsquo;s a little different to debug compared to launching it standalone, but not any more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOS Is Rubbish</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/tos-is-rubbish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 08:12:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/tos-is-rubbish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never noticed it growing up but I see it now, TOS is profoundly flakey. My ST has a TOS 1.62 ROM built in and it does not play nice with hard drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a simple solution to this, use the wonderful open source &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/emutos/emutos&#34;&gt;EmuTOS&lt;/a&gt; instead. Now I&amp;rsquo;m not resourceful enough to go writing EmuTOS to a flash ROM but my ST does have enough RAM that I can easily get away with loading it up from the hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solid Principles: A Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/solid-principles-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 16:49:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/solid-principles-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a single-page cheat sheet that summarised SOLID software development principles, so I made one. For each of the letters in SOLID (Single Responsibility, Open/Closed, Liskov Substitution, Interface Segregation, Dependency Inversion) there are a couple of bullet points explaining the benefits of adopting them and the smells that betray their violation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asp.NET Self-Signed Certificates and Fedora</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/asp-net-self-signed-certs-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 16:12:24 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/asp-net-self-signed-certs-fedora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I spent a bit of time fighting with certificates in an ASP.NET application I&amp;rsquo;m working on. The scenario is we have Blazor Server communicating with a Minimal API. Debugging locally I was struggling to get the two to communicate, with errors like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remote certificate is invalid because of errors in the certificate chain: UntrustedRoot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slight Delay With Bluetooth Mouse in Linux</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/slight-delay-with-bluetooth-mouse-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 21:11:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/slight-delay-with-bluetooth-mouse-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A quick tip here for when a bluetooth mouse takes a moment to react after not being used for a few seconds. Bluetooth autosuspend can be disabled with a negligible power consumption penalty by setting a kernel parameter on boot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQLite.NET in Godot</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/sqlite-net-in-godot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 20:02:53 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/sqlite-net-in-godot/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll talk more about why I think the Godot game engine is a good alternative to Unity as part of my alternatives series of posts, but for now I want to share for posterity&amp;rsquo;s sake how to use SQLite.NET in Godot. Skip to the end to add the one package necessary to get SQLite.NET working in Godot.
For the uninitiated, SQLite.NET is an ORM for SQLite, similar to Entity Framework. SQLite is a good fit for games and I&amp;rsquo;m fond of using an ORM where possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post #1: A Git Trick</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/a-git-trick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 19:37:16 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/a-git-trick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! I&amp;rsquo;ve started a new blog. For my first post I&amp;rsquo;m going to share a Git configuration trick that I often use to work around this dang ol&amp;rsquo; error message when trying to push a locally created branch to a remote repository:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>