<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tips on Garcia&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</title>
    <link>https://rakhama.com/tags/tips/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tips on Garcia&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 13:29:17 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rakhama.com/tags/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scoop Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/scoop-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 13:29:17 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/scoop-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you still downloading &lt;code&gt;.exe&lt;/code&gt; files like some kinda chump? Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://scoop.sh&#34;&gt;Scoop&lt;/a&gt;, a package manager for Windows not too dissimilar to &lt;a href=&#34;https://chocolatey.org&#34;&gt;Chocolatey&lt;/a&gt; which ought to be very familiar to any Linux enthusiast. It&amp;rsquo;s fast, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to use, and it&amp;rsquo;s open source. Yes, Scoop is great but this article is not about extolling the virtues of the package management tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run a Blazor Web Application as Maui Mobile App</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/run-blazor-web-application-as-maui-mobile-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 14:20:14 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/run-blazor-web-application-as-maui-mobile-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took some time to investigate developing a MAUI mobile app that shares business logic with a Blazor web app by way of ViewModels and the like. What I discovered was that MAUI and XAML is a pretty cumbersome framework. My colleague Kael &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaels-kabbage.com/posts/cross-platform-options-a-very-shallow-exploration/#maui-blazor-hybrid&#34;&gt;gave me some insight&lt;/a&gt; on the possibility of building a Blazor app and running that as a MAUI app. After looking into it in more detail I came to the conclusion that having a single application with multiple deployment targets is a more practical approach to cross-platform development. This article serves as a guide to developing a single application that can be deployed as both a website and an Android app. Of course there are a few platform specific things to look out for but they&amp;rsquo;re easily handled as I will demonstrate in this post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All in One Guide to Setting Up Ssh</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/all-in-one-guide-to-setting-up-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 15:59:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/all-in-one-guide-to-setting-up-ssh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This guide is mostly a reference for myself as it&amp;rsquo;s a workflow that I find myself following whenever I set up a new Linux machine. I&amp;rsquo;m sharing it here as I&amp;rsquo;m sure many will find this useful, and it will save me from looking up each distinct step in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also took the opportunity to add some bonus network configuration tips to get the most out of the setup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto Unlock Fedora Encrypted Drive</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/auto-unlock-fedora-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2023 14:32:11 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/auto-unlock-fedora-drive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently installed Fedora on my personal laptop to replace Manjaro as I found Manjaro to be a just a little too flaky for my liking and I know Fedora to be a solid alternative. During installation I was asked if I wanted to encrypt my drives. Now I&amp;rsquo;m not harbouring anything particularly sensitive but I thought it was worth doing, security first and all that; after all, we expect every website to support HTTPS these days so why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well there is the matter of that mildly pesky login prompt on every boot&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluxor for Dummies</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/fluxor-for-dummies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 15:44:33 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/fluxor-for-dummies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mrpmorris/Fluxor&#34;&gt;Fluxor&lt;/a&gt; is a Flux implementation for Blazor in the vein of Redux. It is a state management system designed for larger software systems that encourages immutability of state, pure functions and clean separation of code. Given my fairly basic understanding of the Flux pattern I thought it would be valuable to document what it is at a high level and what&amp;rsquo;s required when using Fluxor to implement the various concepts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blazor With MVVM</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/blazor-with-mvvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 14:34:41 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/blazor-with-mvvm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MVVM is a development pattern that has been around for a while now. It was designed to facilitate the development of WPF applications for Windows and is still used for the likes of &lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/architecture/maui/mvvm&#34;&gt;Maui&lt;/a&gt; apps. I reckon it has a place in Blazor apps as a neat way to separate view from logic, and as a sort of volatile state management for when you don&amp;rsquo;t want state to persist between pages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug Server Hosted Blazor Web Assembly in VS Code</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/debug-server-hosted-blazor-wasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 16:20:25 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/debug-server-hosted-blazor-wasm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A published Blazor WebAssembly instance is just a collection of files that can be loaded into a browser. If these files are hosted on the API, running the API means the UI is running as well, probably from the same address. In this case it&amp;rsquo;s a little different to debug compared to launching it standalone, but not any more complicated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bluetooth Peripherals - Unijoysticle</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/projects/atari-modernisation-project/bluetooth-peripherals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 09:06:42 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/projects/atari-modernisation-project/bluetooth-peripherals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a neat device that allows you to connect bluetooth peripherals to your ST including modern mice and joypads. Out of the box it works well with joypads, but takes a little bit of software tinkering to enable mouse support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USB Floppy Emulator - Gotek</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/projects/atari-modernisation-project/usb-floppy-emulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 08:21:59 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/projects/atari-modernisation-project/usb-floppy-emulator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A quick guide on using a Gotek USB floppy emulator in your ST, conveniently store all your floppy images on a single drive and never have to worry about worn out floppy drive belts again!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TOS Is Rubbish</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/tos-is-rubbish/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 08:12:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/tos-is-rubbish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never noticed it growing up but I see it now, TOS is profoundly flakey. My ST has a TOS 1.62 ROM built in and it does not play nice with hard drives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a simple solution to this, use the wonderful open source &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/emutos/emutos&#34;&gt;EmuTOS&lt;/a&gt; instead. Now I&amp;rsquo;m not resourceful enough to go writing EmuTOS to a flash ROM but my ST does have enough RAM that I can easily get away with loading it up from the hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/projects/atari-modernisation-project/cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 11:13:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/projects/atari-modernisation-project/cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page documents some tips and tricks to help make the most of your ST.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solid Principles: A Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/solid-principles-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 16:49:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/solid-principles-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a single-page cheat sheet that summarised SOLID software development principles, so I made one. For each of the letters in SOLID (Single Responsibility, Open/Closed, Liskov Substitution, Interface Segregation, Dependency Inversion) there are a couple of bullet points explaining the benefits of adopting them and the smells that betray their violation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asp.NET Self-Signed Certificates and Fedora</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/asp-net-self-signed-certs-fedora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 16:12:24 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/asp-net-self-signed-certs-fedora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I spent a bit of time fighting with certificates in an ASP.NET application I&amp;rsquo;m working on. The scenario is we have Blazor Server communicating with a Minimal API. Debugging locally I was struggling to get the two to communicate, with errors like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remote certificate is invalid because of errors in the certificate chain: UntrustedRoot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/projects/atari-modernisation-project/desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 11:01:31 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/projects/atari-modernisation-project/desktop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How to modernise the Atari ST desktop environment, from upgrading to a more modern GEM environment to applying custom wallpapers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slight Delay With Bluetooth Mouse in Linux</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/slight-delay-with-bluetooth-mouse-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 21:11:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/slight-delay-with-bluetooth-mouse-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A quick tip here for when a bluetooth mouse takes a moment to react after not being used for a few seconds. Bluetooth autosuspend can be disabled with a negligible power consumption penalty by setting a kernel parameter on boot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQLite.NET in Godot</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/sqlite-net-in-godot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 20:02:53 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/sqlite-net-in-godot/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll talk more about why I think the Godot game engine is a good alternative to Unity as part of my alternatives series of posts, but for now I want to share for posterity&amp;rsquo;s sake how to use SQLite.NET in Godot. Skip to the end to add the one package necessary to get SQLite.NET working in Godot.
For the uninitiated, SQLite.NET is an ORM for SQLite, similar to Entity Framework. SQLite is a good fit for games and I&amp;rsquo;m fond of using an ORM where possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post #1: A Git Trick</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/a-git-trick/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 19:37:16 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/a-git-trick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! I&amp;rsquo;ve started a new blog. For my first post I&amp;rsquo;m going to share a Git configuration trick that I often use to work around this dang ol&#39; error message when trying to push a locally created branch to a remote repository:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
