<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>software on Garcia&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</title>
    <link>https://rakhama.com/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in software on Garcia&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:08:55 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rakhama.com/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hosting Podman Containers on Systemd with Quadlets</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/hosting-podman-containers-on-systemd-with-quadlets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 13:08:55 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/hosting-podman-containers-on-systemd-with-quadlets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was looking into alternatives to Docker Compose for Podman (yes, there is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.podman.io/en/latest/markdown/podman-compose.1.html&#34;&gt;podman-compose&lt;/a&gt; wrapper that brings similar functionality to Podman), and stumbled across the concept of &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.podman.io/en/latest/markdown/podman-systemd.unit.5.html&#34;&gt;Quadlets&lt;/a&gt;. Well, turns out they&amp;rsquo;re nothing like Docker Compose, perhaps more like Kubernetes or one of them fellas. Indeed, the name Quadlet was supposedly named after a squashed Kubelet. Geddit? Squashed kube? A quad? Ah, never mind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternatives Series: Spotify</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/alternatives-series-spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 15:07:33 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/alternatives-series-spotify/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of questionable ethical behaviours going on with big technology companies these days. Hearing horror stories from Meta (formerly Facebook,) Alphabet (Google,) Amazon, Microsoft and Apple has left me with a rather sour taste in my mouth. I&amp;rsquo;ve personally been stung by bait-and-switch campaigns like when OneDrive revoked large amounts of free storage and LastPass nerfed their free tier subscription. The former was ultimately reversed with a workaround but I was shook; these big companies can make drastic changes to these services I rely on at a whim.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
