<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>alternatives on Garcia&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</title>
    <link>https://rakhama.com/tags/alternatives/</link>
    <description>Recent content in alternatives on Garcia&#39;s Guide to the Galaxy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 14:38:02 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rakhama.com/tags/alternatives/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alternatives Series: Social Media</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/alternatives-series-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 14:38:02 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/alternatives-series-social-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The world is always changing, there&amp;rsquo;s no denying that. But the latest haps have many of us quite worried. Society at large seems to be hurtling towards fascism, a vocal minority of affluent and angry men propped up by big tech dragging us all deeper into the ugliest depths of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I singled out Big Tech there because it&amp;rsquo;s something that probably the majority of us are actively participating in. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be this way! In this post I will outline some of the alternatives available to the big social network platforms, hopefully giving you some inspiration to step away from these incrasingly toxic places.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scoop Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/scoop-upgrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 13:29:17 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/scoop-upgrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you still downloading &lt;code&gt;.exe&lt;/code&gt; files like some kinda chump? Check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://scoop.sh&#34;&gt;Scoop&lt;/a&gt;, a package manager for Windows not too dissimilar to &lt;a href=&#34;https://chocolatey.org&#34;&gt;Chocolatey&lt;/a&gt; which ought to be very familiar to any Linux enthusiast. It&amp;rsquo;s fast, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to use, and it&amp;rsquo;s open source. Yes, Scoop is great but this article is not about extolling the virtues of the package management tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternatives Series: Spotify</title>
      <link>https://rakhama.com/posts/alternatives-series-spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 15:07:33 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rakhama.com/posts/alternatives-series-spotify/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of questionable ethical behaviours going on with big technology companies these days. Hearing horror stories from Meta (formerly Facebook,) Alphabet (Google,) Amazon, Microsoft and Apple has left me with a rather sour taste in my mouth. I&amp;rsquo;ve personally been stung by bait-and-switch campaigns like when OneDrive revoked large amounts of free storage and LastPass nerfed their free tier subscription. The former was ultimately reversed with a workaround but I was shook; these big companies can make drastic changes to these services I rely on at a whim.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
